The previous video I talked about the
growth hormone releasing peptide Tessa
Morlin which is one of the more recent
ones. It came out I believe in 2009
under the name Agria and they also have
agria SW. So today I'm talking about the
old school one. I'm talking about Sir
Morland which came [music] out under the
FDA approved name Gareth and it was
previously used actually in growth
hormone stimulation tests. It was used
in children and then it was also FDA
approved for the application of low
growth hormone. Now, somorin works
similar to being an endogenous analog of
growth hormone releasing hormones and it
tells the anterior pituitary to make
growth hormone which therefore tells the
liver to make IGF-1 which about 70 75%
of all IGF-1 production occurs at the
site of liver and the rest of it occurs
peripherally such as cartilagynous
tissue such as the gastrointestinal
tract as well. Some of the benefits one
could expect with the introduction of a
growth hormone secret. One of the
biggest ones is cognitive fluidity. In
other words, what the literature has
shown us is that as people get older,
they experience cognitive decline. And
with cognitive decline, they lose
fluidity, which is the ability to
demonstrate the movement from one topic
to another. And they have nice verbal,
nice memory recall as well. Whereas
someone who lacks cognitive fluidity,
well, you know, they're not as sharp on
their toes. They don't recall things
with acumen that other people typically
would. In terms of anabolism, IGF-1 and
GH aren't exactly, they're not the most
anabolic of agents, especially when
compared to androgens. Androgens just
outshine IGF-1 and GH so much. But IGF-1
and GH, they can they can increase
protein synthesis. They can increase
nitrogen retention, but they can also
help with the cartilagynous structures.
They help with the repair because, as
you know, if you train a lot, well,
you're going to have breakdown of
tissue. Your body's going to wear out.
So, GH and thus IGF-1 are great for
repairative regenerative type things,
but they aren't inherently the most
anabolic of agents, though. A few other
benefits of IGF-1 is that it can also
increase glycogen synthesis. It can
increase tendon collagen synthesis. It
can prevent mitochondrial breakdown
especially in the meioytes and on top of
that also shares a lot of the same
properties as insulin. In fact IGF-1
shares about 50% the same amino acid
homology as does insulin and it's even
been demonstrated to exert similar
glucose reduction and insulin
sensitizing benefits that insulin does.
Body composition improvements have been
reported in the literature. Even
anecdotally, a lot of athletes, a lot of
bodybuilders particularly will report
that using these type of agents helps
them lean out. And we know this because
GH is great at inducing lipolysis, which
is the breakdown of fatty tissue. So
similar to other GHRPS or growth hormone
releasing peptides, growth hormone
secrets, whatever you want to call them,
sirin is dosed with a subcutaneous
administration, typically done right
before you go to bed. And like the other
GHRPS, you typically want to do it on an
empty stomach to maximize its benefits.
Now, in terms of adverse reactions,
well, some people can demonstrate
fatigue, but hey, if you get fatigue,
guess what? You're going to bed anyway.
And hey, maybe some of that fatigue will
translate to hitting that deep wave
sleep, which is the type of sleep that
really facilitates the production of the
GH pulses. Some people get injection
site reactions. Some people get some
flushing. Some people get some water
retention. Also, some literature shown
that there might be marginal increases
in prolactin and maybe even cortisol.
But believe it or not, there's some
studies that show that at higher doses.
We're talking upwards of 1 milligram per
night. There's some studies that show
that it can even increase FSH and or LH
in men. So if they're hypogonatal, it's
speculated that it could possibly help
increase testosterone in those people
who are hypogonatal,
but it hasn't been thoroughly explored,
nor would I want to try that with a
patient of mine. To be honest with you,
I wouldn't want to try that. In
pediatric dosing and some of the
provocative testing, the dosages were
around 30 micrograms per kilogram. But
if you translate that to an adult dose,
that would be oftentimes in the milligs,
which is quite large for typical adults.
What most the literature supported, what
most compounding pharmacists would
recommend for adults typically is in the
ballpark of about 100 to 400ish
micrograms nightly. As a recap, I've
been familiar with Simorland over a
decade. Used it myself. I think it's
very well tolerated. It's mild at best.
Yeah, I've noticed and appreciated some
deeper, more restorative sleep. If you
train pretty regularly, you'll notice
less doms. You'll notice that your
recovery is a lot better and that your
capacity to push yourself is more well
tolerated.
Hey,
hey,
hey.